# brian:// miranda

<web developer>



Web developer and internet researcher based in Mexico City. I'm also well-versed in UX design and mobile-first development, and I also do research on various online topics, particularly about internet culture, community moderation, misinformation, political activism, internet censorship, open-source software, DRM, platform policy/governance, online communities, online harassment, and the various intersections of mental health and social media.

# Education

## JAN 2011 - MAY 2014 Universidad Tecnológica de México

Licenciatura en Diseño Gráfico

# JUL 2015 - NOV 2016 Universidad Tecnológica de México

Seminario en Diseño Multimedia

# JUL 2018 - NOV 2018 codecademy.com

Build Websites from Scratch Pro Intensive Course

JAN 2020 - APR 2020 coderhouse.com.mx Curso de Desarrollo UX/UI

# Skills & Toolkit

#### Technical:

Advanced HTML & CSS Intermediate JavaScript Bootstrap, jQuery and React.js Git Workflow

### Design:

Adobe XD, Figma and Sketch Adobe CC (AI, PS, DW and AE)

#### **UI/UX Research:**

User Interviews, qualitative/ quantitative survey design and analysis, workshop design.

## General:

Problem solving, critical thinking, team player, project management, fast learner. Native spanish fluency.

# **Experience**

FEB 2012 - AUG 2014 Magicorp México Old Film Restoration Technician

> Digital film restoration using Blackmagic DaVinci Revival. Removed problems such as film grain, dust, dirt and scratches, flicker, and warping from bad film splices.

OCT 2014 - OCT 2015 Muv Lab 2D Animator Internship

Pre-production, scriptwriting, storyboarding and animatics. 2D animation using Toon Boom Harmony and Adobe After Effects. Post-production.

NOV 2015 - APR 2018 Manatí Media Motion Graphic Designer

Motion graphic work for marketing agency. Promotional videos, information screens, internal communication videos for companies, among other things.

DEC 2018 - JUL 2021

# Memórica México / Presidencia de la República Multimedia Design Head of Area

Front-end development and implementation on memoricamexico.gob. Used various technologies, including JavaScript and Bootstrap to help create a government website for historical documents. Designed site ensuring UI/UX feasibility.

DEC 2021 - MAR 2022 PepsiCo, GBS Frito-Lay North America Jr. Multimedia Web Designer

Adaptation of existing visuals for digital tool kits, social media posts, digital ads and other marketing materials for the Frito-Lay North America brand portfolio.

MAY 2022 - OCT 2024 Cafebrería El Péndulo Web Designer

> Site maintenance as well as redesign of certain sections. Also ran email marketing strategy.

# References

#### Felipe Cortina Latapí

Managing Director and Founder // Manatí Media y Axfel S.C. fcortina@axfel.com

#### Kassia Frida Rubi Estrella

Brand Content Manager // PepsiCo kassia.fr@outlook.com

#### María Angélica Santa María Daffunchio

Head of Design // Memórica México / Presidencia de la República angie.smd@gmail.com

#### Aida Fernanda Jiménez Ruvalcaba

Graphic Designer // Cafebrería El Péndulo paidajicama@gmail.com